Don't ask, don't tell is pretty good advice.
How do you ask a coworker out on a date?
This is Doctor Paul, author of Boomer Girls: A Boomer Woman's Guide to Men and Dating and host of Ask Doctor Paul.
Many companies have a no fraternization policy, that means they are not interested in you dating within the company because it can cause problems.
Now, how enforcible is that, I'm not certain.
I'm not certain that HR knows but I know that if an issue comes up, that may be used.
The best advice is don't ask don't tell, take it outside.
If you find someone that you feel you're interested in dating at the office, say to that person, I would like to meet you for coffee, that's easy to chat about a few things after work, at this restaurant.
Do not make it a bar, it's too close.
Go to the restaurant and say look, I'm interested in you, be it male or female, and say I would like to get to know you better.
I do not want anyone to be aware of this at work, it's nobody's business but yours and mine, and so if you feel the same way and you'd like to see me, then I would like to see you but I do not want anyone at the office to be aware of this.
Okay.
So when I said don't ask don't tell, that's exactly what it is.
And you have to have a commitment, both of you, to not have anything stated.
If the other says, well I really don't feel comfortable with that, I don't date people at work, that's it.
Never go there again.
Get the cell phone, get the e-mail, whatever it may be, and then proceed communicating from there.
Don't do the e-mails at work, don't do the cell phone at work, keep that distinctly apart from whatever's going to occur on the outside.